### Jonathan Goessl

San Clemente, California 92672 (773) 656-2624 jgoessl13@gmail.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A reliable and skilled professional with a wealth of skills to include communication, leadership, imagery interpretation, geospatial analysis, technical data and software administration, decisive reasoning, and supervisory experience. Proficient in working autonomously or as an affiliate of a team and is comfortable with applying the skills and knowledge in both problems solving and teaching. Qualifications include:

- Adapting to Change
- Top Secret Clearance SCI
- Knowledge on Windows System Administration
- Training Others
- Leadership Experience
- Technical Customer Service
- Strong Time Management
- ArcGIS Enterprise Savvy
- Proficient Verbal and Written Skills

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Imagery Analyst Specialist Trainer/Staff Supervisor, 2017 – Present

- Expertly managed the development of training programs for Imagery Analysts and Geospatial Analysts through productivity and precision of written documents and presentations.
- Monitored and implemented technical customer service through strong prioritization skills, increasing the resolution of technical issues.
- Monitored complex cataloging and ordering of system software by applying a standard operating procedure for data management.
- Efficiently understand a broad range of GIS software to include the ArcGIS Enterprise, Socet GXP Enterprise, and ENVI.
- Supervising a staff of 30 in daily administrative tasks.
- Forward deployed with Task Force Blue Shield conducting and analyzing geospatial intelligence.

Imagery Analyst Specialist/Maintenance Manager, 2016-2017

- Conveyed and implemented technical customer service through strong prioritization skills, increasing the resolution of technical issues.
- Produced and applied intelligence community analytical tradecraft and writing standards to Geospatial products.
- Identified discrepancies in multiple workstations in the inventory database that would affect the Agency's overall workflow and production.

Main Battle Tank Repairer/Technician, 2012 – 2016

- Supervised a staff of 78 in daily operations, ensuring quality assurance and quality control resulting in a company increase for productivity.
- Expertly managed high energy, fast-paced, and collaborative culture by increasing the crew's morale.
- Organized quality control training for new employees raising the effectiveness of the company by 90%.

# EDUCATION, CERTIFICATIONS, and TRAINING

- Southern New Hampshire University, Bachelor of Science in Geosciences with a Concentration in Natural Resources and Conservation, Manchester, NH; GPA 3.96, October 2019
- ESRI, Portal for ArcGIS: User Workflows, June 2019
- National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Intermediate Geographic Information Systems (GIS) for Analysis, April 2019
- National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Fundamentals of Geographic Information Systems (GIS), April 2019
- BAE Systems Geospatial eXploitation Products, GXP Tactical Products Course, October 2019
- BAE Systems Geospatial eXploitation Products, SOCET GXP v4.3 Essentials, Mapping and Topography, February 2019
- ESRI Migrating from ArcMap to ArcGIS Pro, September 2018
- National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Fundamentals of Processing of Polarimetric Imagery (PI), July 2018
- National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Fundamentals of Spectral Exploitation and Analysis (MSI), July 2018
- ESRI, ArcGIS Pro: Essential Workflows, May 2018
- Marine Corps Intelligence Schools, Critical and Creative Thinking Course, April 2018
- United State Department of Defense, GEOINT Professional Certification-Fundamentals, November 2017; Certification Number: 010113
- BAE Systems Geospatial eXploitation Products, GXP Xplorer for System Administrators, August 2017
- National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Tactical Imagery Analysis Specialist Course, December 2016
- National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, Fundamentals of Full Motion Video (FMV) Exploitation, September 2016

## **VOLUNTEER and ORGANIZTIONS EXPERIENCE**

- Inductee of the National Society of Leadership and Success, 2018 Present
- Corona Nation, 2016 2019
- Team Rubicon, 2019 Present
- The Access Fund, 2017 Present
- American Alpine Club, 2017 Present